Guide to the Pettigrew Papers
Yale University Library
- General Correspondence Files, 1797-1865; Series I:; 4.59' (13 boxes)
  - Goodenough, Edmund, 1785-1845. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1804-27 (Box 5, Folder 238)
    In one letter he thanks Pettigrew for a copy of his Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
  - Goodwin, Charles Wycliffe, 1817-1878. ALS to the Secretary of the B.A.A., 1862 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 239)
    Expresses interest in printing in the "Parthenon" the reports of the proceedings of learned societies, specifically the British Archaeological Association.
  - Gordon, J. E. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1831 or later] (Box 5, Folder 240)
    His seat in Parliament eliminated by the Reform Bill of 1832, Gordon sought another constituency.
  - Gosford, Archibald Acheson, 2d Earl of, 1776-1849. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833-44 (Box 5, Folder 241)
    Agrees to purchase Pettigrew's Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
  - Gosford, Archibald Acheson, 3d Earl of, 1806-1864. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - Gould, Nathaniel. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1850], 1861 (Box 5, Folder 243)
    One letter comments on Cardinal Wiseman and the other indicates that Gould was planning to form a company with Sir Samuel Cunard to prospect for gold in Nova Scotia.
  - Grafton, William Henry FitzRoy, 6th Duke of, 1819-1882. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 244)
    Declines to be a Vice President of the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Granville, Augustus Bozzi, 1783-1872. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 245)
    In one letter discusses a misplaced cloak.
  - Grenville, Thomas, 1755-1846. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1805-42 (Box 5, Folder 246)
    Grenville agrees to become one of Pettigrew's subscribers of the Encyclopedia Britannica.
  - Grey, Charles Grey, 2d Earl, 1764-1845. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1819, 1829 (Box 5, Folder 247)
    In one letter he shows his support for the Royal Humane Society.
  - Grey-Egerton, Sir Philip de Malpas, 1806-1881. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    Declines to become Vice President of the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Guilford, Francis North, 6th Earl of, 1772-1861. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Feb, May (Box 5, Folder 249)
    Declines, because of advanced age, to become affiliated with the British Archaeological Association.
  - Gunn, William, 1750-1841. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Jan 27 (Box 5, Folder 250)
    Seeks Pettigrew's aid for the publication and selling of Gunn's Cartonensia.
  - Gurney, John Hampden, 1802-1862. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Gutch, John Matthew, 1776-1861. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848-54 (Box 5, Folder 252)
    Discusses Richard Gough in one letter.
  - Guthrie, George James, 1785-1856. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1833]-45 (Box 5, Folder 253)
    In one letter, seeks Pettigrew's aid in electing a friend of Guthrie's to a position of Surgeon.
  - Gwilt, Joseph, 1784-1863. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Mar 28 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - Haigh, Daniel Henry, 1819-1879. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Dec 21 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Halford, Sir Henry, bart., 1766-1844. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-37 (Box 6, Folder 256)
    On Pettigrew's attempt to be elected Surgeon in St. James Parish; Halford's opinion of his portrait. Halford mentions that he had had his portrait painted by Sir Thomas Lawrence.
  - Haliburton, James, 1788-1862. 7 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833-48 (Box 6, Folder 257)
    About Haliburton's poor financial condition and his work for Robert Hay. Also mentions Sir Gardner Wilkinson.
  - Hall, Marshall, 1790-1857. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838 Feb 14 (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Halliday, Sir Andrew, 1781-1839. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823, 1826 (Box 6, Folder 259)
    Discusses one of his works in one letter.
  - Hamilton, Henry Parr, 1794-1880. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844-58 (Box 6, Folder 260)
    In one letter Hamilton says that publicly supported church schools should enroll "children of Dissenters" without requiring them to learn any catechism.
  - Hamilton, R., col. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 Jul 21 (Box 6, Folder 261)
    Discusses the work Sandoval; or the Freemason.
  - Hamilton, William Richard, 1777-1859. 7 ALS and 1 LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-45 (Box 6, Folder 262)
    About Hamilton's participation in the British Archaeological Association and the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Hancock, Thomas, 1783-1849. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834, 1842 (Box 6, Folder 263)
    Recommends several friends to Pettigrew. Hancock's writing gives evidence to his Quaker upbringing.
  - Hargrove, William, 1788-1862. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Apr 22 (Box 6, Folder 264)
    About his membership in the British Archaeological Association.
  - Harland, John, 1806-1868. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Sep 10 (Box 6, Folder 265)
    About the British Archaeological Association and several printed works.
  - Harriott, Thomas. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1813 Dec 8 (Box 6, Folder 266)
    About his failing finance due to problems in India.
  - Harrod, Henry, 1817-1871. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Aug 7 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Harrowby, Dudley Francis Stuart Ryder, 3d Earl of, 1831-1900. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851-52 (Box 6, Folder 268)
    About an article he wrote for the British Archaeological Association.
  - Hartshorne, Charles Henry, 1802-1865. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860-61 (Box 6, Folder 269)
    About his affiliation with the British Archaeological Association and several of his works.
  - Haslam, John, 1764-1844. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831-33 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Hatcher, Henry, 1777-1846
    - ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Feb 25 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - ALS to C. R. Smith, 1845 Jul 7 (Box 6, Folder 272)
      Hatcher discusses an essay of his on Roman roads.
  - Hawkins, Caesar Henry, 1798-1884. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1831 or later] (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Hawkins, Edward, 1780-1867. 4 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828]-53 (Box 6, Folder 274)
    In one letter Hawkins asks for any suggestions from Pettigrew for changes in the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Hawkins, Francis, 1794-1877. 2 LS, 9 ALS, and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1835-52 (Box 6, Folder 275)
    Letters discuss some medical matters, Pettigrew's medical works, and his Medical Portrait Gallery. One letter discusses Richard Powell and includes Sir Henry Halford's tribute to him in the 1835 Harveian oration.
  - Hay, Robert, 1799-1863. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841, 1842 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    About Pettigrew's Encyclopedia Egyptiaca, with criticism of its illustrations. Several references to James Haliburton.
  - Heath, Dunbar Isidore, 1816-1888. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 277)
    About Heath's suit in the court of arches.
  - Heath, J. M. 6 ALS and 1 AL (draft) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817-38 (Box 6, Folder 278)
    Discusses finding members for the Philosophical Society.
  - Heberden, William, 1767-1845. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 279)
    Agrees to subscribe to Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Henderson, Alexander, 1780-1863. 2 AL (3d person) to T. J. Pettigrew, [1825 or later] (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Heytesbury, William A'Court, 1st Baron, 1779-1860. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1855 Jul 10 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    About a Congress of the British Archaeological Association to be held on the Isle of Wight.
  - Hill, Sir Rowland, 1795-1879. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1855 Dec 21 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Hill, Thomas, 1760-1840. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827 Mar 20 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Hincks, Edward, 1792-1866. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Jul-Aug (Box 6, Folder 284)
    About archaeological matters, especially Egyptian materials. In one letter, he suggests the fierce rivalry between Albert Way's Archaeological Institute and the British Archaeological Association.
  - Holland, Sir Henry, bart., 1788-1873. 7 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1824-47] (Box 6, Folder 285)
    In one letter he indicates that Sir Everard Home had been a trustee of the Royal College of Surgeons.
  - Hood, Sir Alexander Bateman Periam Fuller-Acland-Hood, bart., 1819-1892. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1856 Jun 30 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    Accepts invitation to be a Vice President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, 1st Baron, 1809-1885. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 287)
    About some meetings of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Hugo, Thomas, 1820-1876. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Mar (Box 6, Folder 288)
    On antiquarian matters.
  - Hume, Abraham, 1814-1884. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849-50 (Box 6, Folder 289)
    Complains about his gout and discusses antiquarian matters pertaining to the British Archaeological Association and the Historic Society of Lancashire and Cheshire.
  - Hunter, Joseph, 1783-1861. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841 May, Jun (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Husenbeth, Frederick Charles, 1796-1872. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to the Council of the B.A.A., 1846-57 (Box 6, Folder 291)
    Mentions Dawson Turner and his "senile indifference" and Lord Stafford.
  - Huskisson, William, 1770-1830. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1818 Jan 9 (Box 6, Folder 292)
    About the Royal Humane Society.
  - Irving, George Vere, 1815-1869. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Jun (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Isaacson, Stephen, 1798-1849. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845-46 (Box 6, Folder 294)
    About the British Archaeological Association and an internal dispute, concerning Thomas Wright, Thomas Bateman, and Isaacson.
  - Jackson, John, Bp. of London, 1811-1885. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854 Jun 5 (Box 7, Folder 295)
  - Jerden, William, 1782-1869. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 May 3 (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Jewitt, Llewellyn Frederick William, 1816-1886. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Oct (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Johnson, James, 1777-1845. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Mar 20 (Box 7, Folder 298)
    Presents a copy of one of his works for Pettigrew to give to the Duke of Sussex.
  - Jones, Harry Longueville, 1806-1870. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848 Jun 2 (Box 7, Folder 299)
    Announces a meeting of the Cambrian Archaeological Association, of which Jones was General Secretary.
  - Jones, Thomas, 1810-1875. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Oct 22 (Box 7, Folder 300)
    On several of Jones's and Pettigrew's works.
  - Jones, William Henry Rich, 1817-1885. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1858 Jun-Jul (Box 7, Folder 301)
    About a paper to be read at a congress of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Julien, [Marc Antoine?]. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Sep 2 (Box 7, Folder 302)
    Discusses his Cosmopolitan Review and includes a prospectus.
  - Just, John, 1797-1852. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-51 (Box 7, Folder 303)
    Two letters discuss Just's membership in the Archaeological Institute; two discuss the British Archaeological Association's congress at Manchester and Lancaster.'
  - Kater, Henry, 1777-1835. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829, 1830 (Box 7, Folder 304)
    One letter is about the election of the Duke of Sussex to the Presidency of the Royal Society.
  - Kean, Charles John, 1811-1868. 1 ALS to James Robinson Planché (1796-1880), 1847 Sep 24 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Keate, Robert, 1777-1857. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1824]-40 (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - Kelly, Patrick, 1756-1842. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830 Jan 30 (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Kemble, Charles, 1775-1854. 1 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Kempe, Alfred John, 1785?-1846. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846 Apr 13 (Box 7, Folder 309)
    About a forthcoming election in the Society of Antiquaries; Kempe gives his opinions on some of the problems of that society.
  - Kerrison, Robert Masters, 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-40 (Box 7, Folder 310)
    One letter is about Pettigrew's grievances against Charing Cross Hospital.
  - King, Richard, 1811?-1876. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 311)
    Invites Pettigrew to a meeting of the Ethnological Society, of which King was Secretary.
  - King, Walker, Bp. of Rochester, 1732-1827. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1815 or later] (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Kingdom, John. ALS to William Salisbury, [after 1831] (Box 7, Folder 313)
    Discusses a poem by Kingdom which dealt with Salisbury's course on biology. Poem, in three parts, included.
  - Kinnaird, Douglas James William, 1788-1830. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823 May 19 (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Knightley, Selina Mary (Hervey), Lady. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1847 Apr 13 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Knox, Vicesimus, d. 1855. ALS to J. G. Children, 1841 Jan 30 (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - Konig, Charles Dietrich Eberhard, 1774-1851. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-[31] (Box 7, Folder 317)
    Thanks the Duke of Sussex for a copy of the Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
  - Lablache, Luigi, 1794-1858
    - 2 ALS and 1 AL (in Italian) to Mr. Albano, [1837 or later] (Box 7, Folder 318)
    - LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838 Aug 22 (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Lamb, Lady Caroline (Ponsonby), 1785-1828. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1823 or later] (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Lamington, Alexander Dundas Ross Wishart Cochrane-Baillie, 1st Baron, 1816-1890. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Apr 30 (Box 7, Folder 321)
    Allows the British Archaeological Association the use of his name at one of its congresses.
  - Lane, Hunter, d. 1853. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 322)
    On recommendations for Lane, including one for a professorship at Edinburgh College.
  - Latham, John, 1761-1843. ASL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 Feb 10 (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Law, George Henry, Bp. of Bath and Wells, 1761-1845. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827 May (Box 7, Folder 324)
    On the Duke of Sussex's library.
  - Lawrence, Sir William, 1783-1867. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841 Nov 16 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Leach, William Elford, 1790-1836. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Nov 22 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Leake, William Martin, 1777-1860. 2 ALS to T.J. Pettigrew and 1 calling card., [1849 or later] (Box 7, Folder 327)
    Discusses a work by [Alexander Craig?] Gibson in one letter.
  - Lee, John, 1783-1866. 17 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825-57 (Box 7, Folder 328)
    About antiquarian works and Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery. One letter indicates that Pettigrew was an original member of the Numismatic Society.
  - Lee, John Edward, 1808-1887. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-53 (Box 7, Folder 329)
    About Lee's subscription to the British Archaeological Association.
  - Lee, Samuel, 1783-1852. 14 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-34 (Box 7, Folder 330)
    About the health of Lee's son and Pettigrew's plans for and the education of his son.
  - Lee, Sarah (Wallis) Bowdich, 1791-1856. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 331)
    On Lee's book, Freshwater Fishes of Great Britain.
  - Leemans, Conrad. 10 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1836-43 (Box 7, Folder 332)
    Discusses some of Leeman's books and antiquarian matters.
  - Lemon, Robert, 1779-1835. 7 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826-31 (Box 7, Folder 333)
    On archival matters. One letter introduces Frederic Hohler, a doctor seeking employment, to Pettigrew.
  - Lemon, Robert, 1800-1867. 3 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826-46 (Box 7, Folder 334)
    Thanks Pettigrew for a copy of his "Medical Superstitions in one letter.
  - Leslie, Charles Robert, 1794-1859. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849 Jan 8 (Box 7, Folder 335)
    Discusses his participation in the testimonial to Robert Vernon.
  - Lete, Thomas. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Jun 3 (Box 7, Folder 336)
    Discusses Pettigrew's dispute with the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Lewis, Frederick Christian, 1779-1856. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Lewis, George Robert, 1782-1871. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840, 1851 (Box 7, Folder 338)
    On two of Lewis's books.
  - Lewis, Griffith George, 1784-1859. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1842 Apr 15 (Box 7, Folder 339)
  - Linley, William, 1771-1835
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - ALS to Mr. Lindsay (Box 7, Folder 341)
      Discusses an auction sale of books.
    - 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1832 or later] (Box 7, Folder 342)
      Agrees to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's books.
  - Liston, Robert, 1794-1847. 9 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1835-46 (Box 7, Folder 343)
    Discusses Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Lloyd, W. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Mar 13 (Box 7, Folder 344)
    Discusses George Manby's rescue device.
  - Loewe, Louis, 1809-1888. 7 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1837-46 (Box 7, Folder 345)
    Discusses some of Loewe's difficulties in England.
  - Londesborough, Albert Denison, 1st Baron, 1805-1860. 43 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS fragment to unidentified [The V. Revd. Dean of ?], [1843-49] (Box 7, Folder 346-347)
    Letters discuss many of the practical aspects of organizing and presiding over the British Archaeological Association. They also discuss Londesborough's resignation from the B. A. A.
  - Lonsdale, James, 1777-1839. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823 Sep 2 (Box 7, Folder 348)
  - Lonsdale, John, Bp. of Lichfield, 1788-1867. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 Jan, Jul (Box 7, Folder 349)
    Discusses a congress of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Lough, John Graham, 1806-1876. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1840 or later] (Box 7, Folder 350)
    Discusses a sculpture for Sir Matthew Ridley.
  - Lower, Mark Anthony, 1813-1876
    - ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Nov 18 (Box 7, Folder 351)
      Letter reveals some of the rivalry between the British Archaeological Association and the Archaeological Institute.
    - 3 ALS to J. R. Planché, 1845-52 (Box 7, Folder 352)
      On antiquarian matters. One letter shows that William Blaauw was a member of the Archaeological Institute. Another includes a list of subscribers to an excavation at Pevensey.
  - Ludolf, comte de [Neopolitan Ambassador]. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830 Apr, Aug (Box 7, Folder 353)
  - Lynch, Christopher. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851-53 (Box 7, Folder 354)
    Discusses of Agnes Strickland's work on the queens of England, especially Mary of Modena.
  - Macdonald, Lawrence, 1799-1878. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1830 or later] (Box 8, Folder 355)
  - McGrigor, Sir Charles Roderic, bart., b. 1811. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1859 or later] (Box 8, Folder 356)
    Letter describes an interview with Garibaldi.
  - McGrigor, Sir James, bart., 1771-1858. 7 ALS, 1 LS, 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-54 (Box 8, Folder 357)
    On the Duke of Sussex's candidacy for the Presidency of the Royal Society; Pettigrew's works on mummies and his Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Mackenzie, Robert Shelton, 1809-1880. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844 Sep 19 (Box 8, Folder 358)
    Asks for personal information from Pettigrew for a Dictionary of Living Authors to be written by Mackenzie.
  - Mackinnon, William Alexander, 1789-1870. 7 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1828-37] (Box 8, Folder 359)
    Agrees to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's books and offers several of his own to the Duke of Sussex.
  - Maitland, Samuel Roffey, 1792-1866. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1838-48] (Box 8, Folder 360)
    About a copy of Pettigrew's Bibliotheca Sussexiana which had been given to the Archbishop of Canterbury.
  - Maltby, Edward, Bp. of Durham, 1770-1859. 23 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1842]-52 (Box 8, Folder 361)
    Letters discuss various matters concerning the Society of Antiquaries, the British Archaeological Association, and the education of Pettigrew's son and attempts to secure his employment. John Rokewode's death and Sir John Coleridge are mentioned.
  - Manby, George William, 1765-1854. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830 Aug 28 (Box 8, Folder 362)
    Attempts to gain the Duke of Sussex's recognition of his work.
  - Mandelsloh, count (Würtemberg Minister to Gr. Brit.). 1 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1826]-35 (Box 8, Folder 363)
    Seeks Pettigrew's help concerning some antiquarian problems.
  - Mangles, James, 1786-1867. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew., 1834-42 (Box 8, Folder 364)
    One letter discusses Sir John Gardner Wilkinson's return to England and an expedition he contemplated organizing, as well as various antiquarian matters.
  - Manvers, Charles Herbert Pierrepont, 2d Earl, 1778-1860. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Jul 9 (Box 8, Folder 365)
    Manvers declines an invitation to become a vice president of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Markland, James Heywood, 1788-1864. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840 May 28 (Box 8, Folder 366)
    Declines to become a member of the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Marrable, Frederick, 1818-1872. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Feb 20 (Box 8, Folder 367)
    Thanks Pettigrew for his support of his admission to the Athenaeum.
  - Marsden, William, 1754-1836. ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Jun (Box 8, Folder 368)
    Declines an invitation to subscribe to Pettigrew's work on mummies.
  - Marshall, William Calder, 1813-1894. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851-58 (Box 8, Folder 369)
  - Martin, Sir James Ranald, 1793-1874. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 370)
  - Martin, Leopold Charles, 1817-1889. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Jun 20 (Box 8, Folder 371)
    Seeks permission to make sketches of some Roman artifacts in Pettigrew's possession.
  - Maton, William George, 1774-1835. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1825 or later] (Box 8, Folder 372)
    On medical matters.
  - Maugham, Robert, d. 1862. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1824 Apr (Box 8, Folder 373)
    One letter seeks Pettigrew's advice on the publication of a "Philomathic Journal", apparently a journal published by the Incorporated Law Society.
  - Mayer, Joseph, 1803-1886. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1849, 1850 (Box 8, Folder 374)
  - Mayo, Herbert, 1796-1852. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1837 or later] (Box 8, Folder 375)
  - Melfort, George Drummond, 6th Duke of, 1807-1902. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1856 Jul 4 (Box 8, Folder 376)
    On Melfort's bill for compensation before the House of Commons.
  - Merivale, John Herman, 1779-1844. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1836 Jul-Nov (Box 8, Folder 377)
    On Merivale's poor health which forces him to resign from the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Merriman, Samuel, 1771-1852. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-38 (Box 8, Folder 378)
    Mention of several of Pettigrew's works.
  - Meyrick, Sir Samuel Rush, 1783-1848. 11 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1827-47 (Box 8, Folder 379)
    About a series of lectures Meyrick gave and various internal problems facing the British Archaeological Association.
  - Monk, James Henry, Bp. of Gloucester and Bristol, 1784-1856. ALS to C. R. Smith, 1846 Apr 17 (Box 8, Folder 380)
  - Montfort, Henry Bromley, Lord, 3d Baron of Horseheath, 1773-1851. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826 Sep 28 (Box 8, Folder 381)
  - Moodie, John. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816-17 (Box 8, Folder 382)
    On Pettigrew's work on Dr. Lettsom.
  - Moore, James Carrick, 1762-1860. 3 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838-40 (Box 8, Folder 383)
    Seeks Pettigrew's support for his admission to the Athenaeum and discusses Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Moreau, César
    - 2 ALS (in French), 2 LS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 document, signed, 1827-36 (Box 8, Folder 384)
      Announces Pettigrew's admission into the Société Académique de Médicine de Marseille. Discusses that society and the Société Française de Statistique Universelle. Enclosures: Prospectus for Voyage en Égypte, et en Nubie, et lieux circonvoisons by J.J. Rifaud (See Rifaud, J.J. for an identical copy), and cover of Catalogue Raisonné et Historique des Antiquités Découvertes in Égypte, by Joseph Passalacqua, signed by author, 1827.
    - LS to the Duke of Sussex, 1831 Feb 28 (Box 8, Folder 385)
      Offers Sussex membership in the Société Française de Statistique Universelle.
  - Morgan, John Minter, 1782-1854. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830-33 (Box 8, Folder 386)